Ricardo Patiño

<u>rickpatinor@gmail.com</u>

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/ricardopatino1

https://github.com/Ricardo-Patino

(+506) 88795100

Network Support Engineer with experience in Coding solutions, I have created applications in React.js, Python. Using HTML, CSS, Ajax, Bootstrap, JavaScript. Accurate, precise and detailed. I can devote myself to a wide variety of tasks that require attention to data and the application of knowledge and experience.

Technical Skills

Programming Languages and Frameworks

HTML	2+ yrs	• • • •
Java Script	1+ yrs	• • • • •
Bootstrap	1+ yrs	• • • •
CSS	2+ yrs	••••

Databases, Tools & Environments

VS Code	1+ yrs	• • • • •
Visual Studio	1+ yrs	• • • • •

Application Lifecycle Management

SQL Server	1+ yrs	• • • • •
My SQL	1+ yrs	• • • • •

Languages

Spanish	Native
English	C1

Work Experience

Campaign Manager

Oct 2021 - Jan 2022

Movable Ink

- -Professional Practice, email Developer
- Build dynamic content using HTML/CSS/JavaScript.
- Answer and manage campaign tickets.
- -Auto QA, make sure it meets all the requirements (zero errors).
- Track your time for each build.
- Manage a growing portfolio of client campaigns.

Network Support Specialist

Dec 2018 - Oct 2021

Sykes - CISCO

- Provide technical support and product information.
- Configure Network access profiles on routers and switches.
- -Configure and reset Network account access. Phone, email and chat support for Cisco Products.
- Network analysis to improve Cisco performance on Wifi systems and help coworkers to clarify questions.

Network Tech Support

Nov 2016 - Dec 2018

LogMeIn -Teleperformance Costa Rica

List technical skills used

- Support on; BoldChat, Bold 360, GotoAssist, Service Desk, LogMeIn Rescue. Windows, Apple, Servers, wireless Networks.
- Respond and resolve routine and 2nd-level hardware/software service tickets.
- HTML configuration for boldchat platform and tools.
- Diagnose and fix application and hardware issues and advanced connectivity problems..
- Create and maintain documentation and training materials, using standard templates, to train new team members.

Personal Projects

Hotel Villa Grace Website

Hotel Villa Grace

Develop a free hosting website for a family business, Deployed using HTML, CSS and Javascript, Javascript Libraries..

Dic 2021 -Actually

First working-live website.

Responsive to mobile and desktop users.

Live chat platform.

https://rickpatinor.wixsite.com/hotelvillagrace

Education & Certifications

Degree/Certification year achieved

4Geeks Academy - FullStack Software Development	2021 - 2021
Universidad Latina de Costa Rica - Bach Business	2007 - 2010
Cisco Networking Academy - Cisco CCNA	2019 - 2020

References & External Links

1. Danil Yépez	Founder at Resonance Costa Rica	88180262	pure2live@gmail.com
2. Ana Catalina Hernánde:	z Health Services Admi student CCSS	87816801	catichacon2016@gmail.com
3. Josué Palma	Commercial Manager AT&T, Mexico	60793939	jpal,ma16@hotmail.com